背景音乐：Last Rose of Summer (Thomas Moore)
艾宾镇广告公司
书名为：《好人难寻》（A Good Man Is Hard to Find）
你是雷德•韦尔比?
You Red Welby?
是的 女士 您找我什么事?
Yes, ma'am. How may I help you?
我听说你负责德林克沃特路的
I heard there's three billboards out on Drinkwater Road...
那三块广告牌的租赁工作 是么?
you're in charge of renting them out, that right?
我都不知道德林克沃特路还有广告牌....
I didn't know we had any billboards out on Drinkwater...
- 德林克沃特路在哪? - 过西兹摩尔那的一条路
- Where is Drinkwater Road? - There's a Road out past the Sizemore.
是个岔道 高速公路开通后就没人走这条路了
Turn-off, nobody uses since the freeway got put in.
你说的对
You are right.
那是有三块广告牌 从1986年开始就没人再用过这三块广告牌了
Got three billboards out there. Nobody's put nothing up out there since... 1986.
最后登出的是"哈吉斯"牌尿不湿的广告
That was 'Huggies'.
要租用这三块广告牌一年须付多少钱?
How much to rent out all three of 'em the year?
一整年?
A year?
那三块广告牌 放置在那样一条荒无人烟的道路上
You wanna pay for three billboards on a road no-one goes down
你确定要租一整年?
unless they got lost or they're retards, for a year?
租不租 韦尔比 你给个痛快话好吧?
Quick, ain't ya, Welby?
好吧..
Well...
现在艾宾镇的广告行业不景气
since what I say goes these days down at the Ebbing Advertising Desk,
所以我保证让你这份钱花得不冤枉
I'm gonna strike you a real good deal on those billboards,
你刚才说你的名字是?
now, what was it you said your name was, Mrs...?
法律规定广告牌上哪些话能说 哪些话不能说?
What's the law on what ya can and cannot say on a billboard?
我想肯定不能有诋毁他人的内容吧
I assume it's ya can't say nothing defamatory,
还不能说"操""尿"或者"逼" 对吧?
and ya can't say, 'Fuck' 'Piss' or 'Cunt'. That right?
还有..
Or...
菊花
Anus.
那就没问题了
Well I think I'll be alright then.
这是第一个月的费用 5000块够用了吧
Here's five thousie for the first month. I assume that'll cover it.
这是我要在广告牌上登出的话
Here's what the billboards oughta say.
你顺便草拟一份我们交易的合约吧
Why don't ya draw up a little contract betwixt us while you're at it,
合约要写明现在那些广告牌除了我没人可以租用 好吧?
make sure nobody rents them billboards out from under me?
我猜你就是安琪拉•海耶斯的妈妈吧
I guess you're Angela Hayes' mother.
是的 我是她的妈妈
That's right, I'm Angela Hayes' mother.
我叫米尔德里德
Name's Mildred.
我什么时候能看到广告牌已经登好了?
How long before you've got 'em put up?
哦 你看星期日..
Oh, shall we say by...
复活节那天如何?
Easter Sunday?
那天可在合适不过了
That'd be perfect.
广告牌：怎么回事 威洛比警长？
- 这他么是什么? - 什么?
- Hey! What the hell's this?! - Que?
- "警察局长威洛比怎么还?"还什么? - 你说什么啊?
- "How come Chief Willoughby?" what? - What?
- 对 后面是"还"什么 - 不知道你说什么
- Yeah! - Huh!
"怎么还"后面是什么?
How come what?
你说的什么啊?
What?!
你给我听好 你这个南美杂种 最好把事情给我解释清楚
Listen, you  fucking beaner, I better start getting some straight answers outta you
把那玩意给我放下
you Put that down.
广告牌：还没有抓到凶手？
这他么是什么?
What the Hell is this?
嘿 你
Hey you?
这他么是什么?
What the fuck is this?
什么他么是什么? - 就这个
- What the fuck is what? - This! This!
- 我看是广告吧 - 什么的广告?
- Advertising, I guess. - Advertising what?
比较隐晦的那种吧
Something obscure?
对 是挺隐晦的
I'll say! Yeah!
我是不是在哪见过你?
Don't I know your face from some place?
- 我不知道 你见过我吗? - 见过
- I dunno, do ya? - Yeah.
我见过你
Yeah, I do.
如果我想抓你的话 现在就可以
I could arrest you right now, if I wanted to.
- 凭什么抓我?- 凭..你随地吐痰 你违反了..
- For what? - For... emptying out your bucket there. It's against the...
那些禁止破坏环境的法律
being bad against the environment laws.
在这之前呢
Before you do that,
迪克森警官
Officer Dixon,
我建议你去那边的第一个广告牌看看
How about you go have yourself a look at that first billboard over there,
看完之后再跟我说什么他妈的破坏环境
and then we can have ourself a conversation about the motherfucking environment.
好不好?
How about that?
我了个擦
Fuck me.
别接...
Don't...
迪克森 你个混球 我正跟我家人一起吃复活节晚餐呢...
Dixon, you goddam asshole, I'm in the middle of my goddam Easter dinner...
抱歉我说脏话哈 乖宝宝们
Sorry, kids.
我知道 局长 抱歉这个时候给你家里打电话 但是...
I know, Chief, and I'm sorry for calling ya at home and all, but uh,
我想我们遇到麻烦了
I think we've got kind of a problem...
广告牌：惨遭奸杀
怎么回事 威洛比局长？
还没有抓到凶手？
惨遭奸杀
不 回去
No. No. Go back.
好的
Alright.
德妮丝 不好意思我来晚了
Sorry I'm late, Denise.
那些用来恶心警察的广告牌已经登出来吧?
Did you put up those billboards to fuck with the cops yet?
是的
They're up.
干个漂亮 姐们 别让那帮警察好受
You go, girl! You go fuck those cops up!
你他么脑子怎么想的 韦尔比 居然让那些话登在广告牌上
What the fuck do you think you're doing, Welby, buncha billboards like that,
你难道没考虑这么做需要承担法律后果吗?
you didn't think there'd be some kinda ramifications? Legally?
什么法律后果啊  塞德里克?
What's the legal ramifications, Cedric?
你想让我给你这样的混混解释有什么法律后果吗?
You want me to explain the legal ramifications, a little punk like you?
你不配叫我塞德里克
And don't call me Cedric.
我没违反法律 事实上 我什么也没违反
Ain't contravening no laws on propriety, ain't contravening no laws on any fucking thing.
- 我查过相关规定 - 是吗?你在哪查的?
- I checked all this up. - Oh yeah, where'd you check all this up?
在..
In a...
在一本书里查的 - 哪本书啊 天才?
- book. - Which book, genius?
书名叫《滚犊子 查什么跟你没关系》
Book called 'Suck my ass, it's none o' your business'.
惨了
Fuck.
这个租广告牌或者这些租广告牌的人
How long has this person, or persons,
准备租多久?
rented these billboards out for?
哦 一年
Oh, the year.
她的已付金额够租多久的?
And how long she actually paid for?
一年
The year.
原来租广告牌的是个女的 是吧?
So it's a she, isn't?
我无法向你透露这样的信息 局长先生
Ain't at liberty to divulge that kinda information, Chief.
米尔德里德•海耶斯 是她吧?
Mildred Hayes, perhaps?
我无法向你透露这样的信息 局长先生
Ain't at liberty to divulge that kinda information, Chief.
你想跟艾宾镇警局作对是不是 雷德?
Do you really wanna fuck with the Ebbing Police Department, Red?
是不是?
Do ya?
可能是吧
I guess.
- 他说什么?当你面说的? - 他没犯任何罪
- He said what?! To your face?! - No crime has been committed here.
不是吧 诽谤名誉不是犯罪吗?
C'mon Defamation of character ain't a crime?
她如果只是在问一个问题 就不能算是诽谤罪
It isn't defamation if she's simply asking a question.
- 你是白痴吗? - 别骂我是白痴 迪克森
- What are you, an idiot? - Don't call me an idiot, Dixon.
我没骂你是白痴啊 我只是问你是不是个白痴 这只是个问题而已
I didn't call you an idiot. I asked if you was an idiot. It was a question.
你被他套路了 塞德里克
He got ya, Cedric!
- 得了吧 我受够了 - 你不能带情绪去工作
- That's it. C'mon man. - Don't go fly off the handle!
这种货色你怎么还给他留在局里? - 本质上来说 他是个好人
- Why in hell you keep that man on? - He's a good man. At heart.
- 他虐待了一名被拘留的嫌疑人 - 并没有..
- He tortured a guy in custody, Bill. - There was no...
切实证据证明他干了那件事
real evidence to support that.
把那广告牌给我撤了
Take 'em down.
啥? - 把那个垃圾广告牌给我撤了
- Hah? - Take that shit down.
- 把什么垃圾撤了? - 嘿 小子
- Take what shit down? - Hey boy.
你以为我不敢在这条大街上就干掉你吗 雷德?
You think I wouldn't take you out, right here on Main Street, Red?
我以为你只敢干掉黑人呢 迪克森...
I Thought you only take out black dudes, Dixon...
够了 住手
That's it. No no.
住手  你再碰我下试试 你个混账东西
Stop it! Don't you ever fucking touch me, you motherfucker.
你是不是喝多了?
Are you drunk?
你现在是不是喝多了? - 起来
Are you drunk right now? - Get up
反正那条小路也没人去
nobody never goes down that road, anyways.
能去那的人除非是走丢了或者是智商有问题
Unless they got lost, or they're retards.
您只须注意不用紧张 说话自然点就好
Well, don't be nervous, is the main thing, and it'll go just fine.
别盯着摄像头 等那车过去我们就开始
Don't look into the camera, obviously. Let's hold for this car.
倒计时3 2 1
In three, two, one.
那么 米尔德里德•海耶斯 你为什么要把这些话登上广告牌呢?
So, Mildred Hayes, why did you put up these billboards?
是这样的 我的女儿安琪拉 7个月前她遭到绑架后被奸杀了
My daughter, Angela, was abducted, raped and murdered seven months ago,
就在我身后这条小路上
on this self-same stretch o' road here,
你看什么呢 老妈? 智障新闻吗?
Whatcha watching, Momma? The stupid news?
本地警察似乎只在乎虐待黑人嫌犯
It seems like the local police department is too busy goin' round torturing black folks
却不去调查真正的犯罪
to be bothered doing anything about solving actual crime,
我想这些广告牌能让他们更专心工作一些
I thought these here billboards might concentrate their minds some.
妈的
Fuck.
实话跟你说 我都不知道警察现在都在做些什么
I don't know what the police are doing, to be honest with you.
我只知道我女儿那已火化的尸体
I do know my daughter's burnt body
埋于六英尺的地下时 这帮警察却吃着甜甜圈
is lying six feet under the ground while they're eating Krispy Kremes
每天就抓抓在停车场玩滑板的小孩
and busting eight year-olds for skateboarding in parking lots.
那为什么在单独把威洛比局长的名字登出来呢?
And Chief Willoughby, why single him out?
他不是警察的头头么?必须有人为此事承担责任
Well, he's the head of 'em, ain't he? The buck's gotta stop at somewhere.
由威洛比局长承担责任吗?
And the buck stops at Willoughby?
对 就由他来承担 他不承担谁承担
Yeah, the buck stops at Willoughby. Dead right it does.
你还好吗?
You alright there, fella?
看来是有人向我们宣战了啊
Looks like we got a war on our hands.
能跟你谈谈吗?
Can we talk?
海耶斯女士 我愿意付出一切代价抓住害死你女儿的嫌疑犯
I'd do anything to catch the guy who did it, Mrs. Hayes.
不过我得跟您解释一下 现场获取的嫌疑人DNA与我们抓捕的任何人都不匹配
But when the DNA don't match no-one who's ever been arrested,
与全国所有记录在案的罪犯的也都不匹配
and when the DNA don't match any other crime nationwide,
从您女儿离家到我们发现她的尸体这段期间
and when there wasn't a single eyewitness from the time she left your house
没有一个目击证人 这种情况下
to the time we found her, well,
我们能做的确实有限
right now there ain't too much more that we can do
你可以把全镇年龄大于8岁的男性血液
you Could pull blood from every man and boy in this town,
都采集起来进行DNA比对啊
over the age of eight.
美国民权法不允许我们按你说的这种做法来调查 海耶斯女士
There's civil rights laws prevents that, Mrs. Hayes,
如果他只是路过我们镇呢...
and what if he was just passing thru town...
那就采集全国8岁以上男性的血液啊
Pull blood from ever' man in the country, then.
那如果他只是路过我们国家呢?
And what if he was just passing thru the country?
如果是我说的算的话
If it was me,
我会建立一个数据库
I'd start up a database,
全国所有男性出生时 把他们的相关数据存到数据库里
every male baby what's born, stick 'em on it,
一旦他们做了违法的事 就在数据库中对照检索
and as soon as they done something wrong, cross reference it
100%确认匹配无误后
make a hundred percent certain it was a correct match,
就杀了他们
then kill 'em.
呃 你这种做法
Yeah, well, there's
美国民权法也绝对不会支持你的
definitely civil rights laws prevents that.
我用尽所有办法去追查嫌犯
I'm doing everything I can to track him down,
所以广告牌上的话对我来说很不公平
I don't think those billboards is very fair.
威洛比 你在这跟我像个娘们似的磨叽的时候
The time it's took you to get out here whining like a bitch, Willoughby,
可能就有某个女孩正在被残忍的杀害
some other poor girl's probably out there being butchered right now,
不过我很庆幸你终于知道干点正事了 这点我可以承认
but I'm glad you've got your priorities straight, I'll say that for ya.
米尔德里德 还有件事我得跟你说
There's something else, Mildred.
我患了癌症
I got cancer.
- 我要死了 - 我知道
- I'm dying. - I know it.
啊?
Huh?
我知道 几乎全镇的人都知道了
I know it. Most everybody in town knows it.
那你还在广告牌上写那些话?
Then you still putting up those billboard?
广告牌上的话也只有在你活着的时候能起点作用 对吧?
Well, they wouldn't be as effective after you croak, right?
看啊
Well looky looky,
这不是整件事开始的始作俑者么...
if it ain't the instigator of this whole goddam affair in the first place...
迪克森 我可不是什么始作俑者
I didn't instigate shit, Dixon...
正跟个侏儒打台球呢
Playing pool against the town midget.
他说的对 雷德 你就是在跟侏儒打台球呢
He's right, Red, you are playing pool against the town midget.
他可是个警察 观察力强着呢
Well he's a cop, y'know, he's observant.
你知道么 从你还是个流鼻涕的小崽子的时候开始
You know, I always disliked you, Red,
我就一直不喜欢你 雷德
ever since you was a snotty little child,
看你现在这样也没比小时候强多少 还是个流鼻涕的小崽子
which you still look like. A snotty little child.
那太遗憾了 我一直都以为你非常优秀
Well that's unfortunate. I always thought you was great.
包括你的名字 "雷德•韦尔比"
Even your name, 'Red Welby'.
我连你的名字都讨厌
Even your name I disliked.
呵呵 随你便吧
Well... okay.
这名字听着像你是个该死的共产党之类的
Like you was some kind of a goddam Communist or something,
- 还引以为傲呢 - 不是的
- and proud of it. - No,
是因为我头发是红色的
it's cos I got red hair.
你知道古巴人看到同性恋会怎么做吗 韦尔比?
Do you know what they do to fagots down in Cuba, Welby?
哇哦 这问题可出格了
Wow, that's left-field...
古巴人看到同性恋会怎么做 迪克森?
No, what do they do to fagots down in Cuba, Dixon?
古巴人会杀死他们
They kill 'em!
对这点我可是持反对意见的 你没想到吧
Which, it might surprise you to learn, I am against.
我不知道古巴人是不是见同性恋就杀 迪克森
I'm not sure if they do kill fagots down in Cuba, Dixon.
虽然古巴人对待同性恋时
I know Cuba's human rights record is pretty deplorable
人权什么的都是浮云 但见一个杀一个?
when it comes to homosexuality, but killing 'em?
你确定你想的不是美国怀俄明州
（注：怀俄明州歧视同性恋严重 2014年才承认同性婚姻合法）
Are you sure you ain't thinking of Wyoming?
总在这抖机灵
Always with the smart-ass...Jesus.
他挺棒的 不是吗?
He's quite good, isn't he?
威洛比是个好人 嘿 看着我
Willoughby's a good man. Hey look at me.
看着我 我现在不是在跟你好好说话吗?
Hey look at me. I'm talking nice to you now, am I?
我现在跟你好好说话
I'm talking nice to you.
他真的是个好人 在他余下的日子里
He's a good man, really. He shouldn't have this be the only thing he thinks about,
他不该被这些破事烦心
the last months left to him.
什么余下的日子?
The last months what?
哦 你还不知道啊
Oh. You didn't know.
他得了胰腺癌
Yeah. Pancreatic.
下一杆轮到我打了
I'm up next
你们这帮老太太别在这絮叨了
You old ladies quit yakking.
- 真没礼貌 - 嘿 米尔德里德
- Rude. - Hey Mildred.
那天我看你上电视了
Saw you on TV the other day.
- 是吗? - 是啊 你很上镜
- Oh yeah? - Yeah, you looked good.
我是说
I mean, y'know,
你在镜头面前讲话条理很清晰
you came across really good, in the things you were saying.
我可不认为你讲话条理很清晰
I didn't think you came across really good in the things you were saying.
我认为你说的都是不经大脑的话
I thought you came across stupid-ass.
你是不是该回家找你妈妈了 迪克森?
Ain't it about time you got home to your momma, Dixon?
不 现在还没到我回家找我妈的时候
No it ain't time I got home to my momma.
我跟她说我晚上12点之前不回家
I told her I was gonna be out 'til twelve. Actually.
天啊
Jesus!
现在是我跟你对局了 米尔德里德
That's me versus you, Mildred!
嘿 罗比 我觉着那个侏儒想跟我发生超友谊关系...
Hey Robbie? I think that midget wants to get in my pants...
蒙哥马利神父
Father Montgomery.
米尔德里德 这么晚还来打搅你 非常抱歉
Mildred. I'm sorry for calling on you so late, but.
我得说罗比对我的招待非常周全
I must say Robbie's been the consummate host.
不过他刚才正要跟我说今天过得不怎么顺什么的
Despite his having, he was just telling me, something of a tricky day at school.
不 没什么 就是队里有些人对我说了些不太好的话
Oh, no, just some of the guys on the team was giving me crap.
说什么了? 就说你那广告牌的事呗 米尔德里德
Crap about what? About the billboards, Mildred.
就因为这个 所以我才来这想跟你聊聊
Which is, uh, kind of what I've come to have a word with you about,
好啊 聊吧
Oh. Proceed.
我知道你很不容易 米尔德里德
I know how hard it's been for you, Mildred,
过去这一年 我们都很感同身受
this past year. We all do.
如果你有什么需要我们帮忙的话
And if there's ever anything that you need,
我们都会伸出援手的 一直都会
we'll be there for you. Always.
但镇里的人都知道威廉•威洛比是个什么样的人
But the town also knows what kind of a man William Willoughby is.
而且他们也都不支持你广告牌上说的那些话
And the town is dead set against these billboards of yours.
你做过民意调查了 是吧 神父?
Took a poll, did ya, Father?
米尔德里德 如果你能一直坚持来教堂的话
You know Mildred, If you hadn't stopped coming to church,
你最起码能了解到人们对此事的一些感受
you'd had a little bit more understanding of the depth of people's feelings.
周日有十多个人因为此事来教堂找我
I had more than a dozen people come up to me on Sunday.
所以你说的对 我做了民意调查
So, yes, I took a poll.
在安琪拉这件事上 每个人
Everybody is with you...
都会跟你在同一战线
about Angela.
但是在广告牌这件事上 没人支持你
Nobody is with you about this.
你知道我今天在想什么吗?
Y'know what I was thinking about today?
我在想洛杉矶那帮街头匪帮
I was thinking 'bout those street gangs they
跛子帮和血帮
got in Los Angeles, the Crips and the Bloods?
我在想一些当时提出来的新法律
I was thinking about that buncha new laws they
我记得可能是八零年代提出来的吧
came up with, in the 1980's I think it was,
新法律是用来打击那些街头帮派 像跛子帮和血帮那样的帮派
to combat those street-gangs, those Crips and those Bloods.
如果我没记错的话 那些新法律的主旨是说
And, if I remember rightly, the gist of what those new laws were saying was
如果你加入了这些帮派 跟他们一起混
if you join one of these gangs, and you're running with 'em,
某天晚上 在你毫不知情的情况下
and down the block one night, unbeknownst to you,
在某个街头 你的跛子帮兄弟或是血帮兄弟 开枪扫了一家店或是用刀捅了一个人
one of your fellow Crips, or your fellow Bloods, shoot up a place, or stab a guy,
即使你对此一无所知
well, even though you didn't know nothing about it,
即使你可能只是站在一个街角
even though you may've just been standing on
忙着你自己的事
a streetcorner minding your own business,
这些新法律规定说
what these new laws said was
你也应受到法律制裁
you are still culpable.
你会受到法律制裁 是因为当初你选择加入了
You are still culpable, by the very act of joining
跛子帮或者血帮
those Crips, or those Bloods, in the first place.
神父 这事令我陷入沉思
Which got me thinking, Father,
这件事整体上看跟你们这些神棍没什么区别 是吧?
that whole type of situation is kinda like your Church boys, ain't it?
你们穿同款式的衣服 你们有自己的聚点
You've got your colors, you've got your clubhouse,
你们就是 我想想用什么词好 一个帮派
you're, for want of a better word, a gang.
你在楼上抽着烟 读着圣经的时候
And if you're upstairs smoking a pipe and reading a bible
你们帮派里的神父正在楼下强奸一个辅祭男童
while one of your fellow gang members is downstairs fucking an altar boy then,
神父 就如跛子帮和血帮一样
Father, just like the Crips, and just like the Bloods,
你也应当受到制裁
you're culpable.
因为你们是一个帮派的
Cos you joined the gang, man.
我才不在乎你是否从没干过 从没见过或是从没听过这样的事
And I don't care if you never did shit or never saw shit or never heard shit.
你们是一个帮派的
You joined the gang.
所以你也应该受到制裁
You're culpable.
一个人受到了制裁
And when a person is culpable
原因是强奸了一个辅祭男童或者随便哪一个男童
to altar-boy-fucking, or anykinda-boy-fucking,
这方面你们可没什么忌口的
I know you guys didn't really narrow that down,
而这样的人是无权到我家来
, then he kinda forfeit the right to come into my house and say
对我 我的生活 我的女儿或是对我的广告牌指手画脚的
anything about me, or my life, or my daughter, or my billboards.
所以呢 神父 我劝你还是喝完你的茶
So, why don't you just finish your tea there, Father
然后从我的厨房里滚出去
And get the fuck outta my kitchen.
不管怎么样 还是谢谢您能来我们家 神父
But thanks for coming up anyway, Father.
你最近感觉如何 威廉
How you been feeling, Bill?
哦 就是感觉我的主要脏器部位长了癌细胞
Oh, like I got cancer in a major organ.
我得跟你说 在米尔德里德•海耶斯广告牌那件事上 我们都是支持你的
Well I just want you to know, we're all on your side about this Mildred Hayes thing...
别在我耳朵边哔哔这件事了
If I have to hear that one more fucking time...!
我受够了 我不能浪费我不多的时间了
I'm done with this shit. I can't waste my life waiting.
别他妈看漫画书了 把海耶斯案件资料拿给我
Stop reading fucking comics and Get me the file on the Hayes case.
安琪拉•海耶斯的案子还是米尔德里德•海耶斯的案子?
The Angela Hayes case or the Mildred Hayes case?
米尔德里德•海耶斯没犯罪 何来案子一说
There is no Mildred Hayes case.
我们正式接到两起对广告牌的投诉 所以呢...
We've had two official complaints about the billboards, so, actually...
谁投诉的?
From who?
一个眼睛长的很搞笑的女士
A lady with a funny eye...
和一个胖牙医
and a fat dentist.
给我安琪拉•海耶斯案子的资料
Give me the file on the Angela Hayes case.
"一个眼睛长得很搞笑的女士"
"A lady with a funny fucking eye",
你可真专业
Jesus Christ.
昨晚出去嗨了?
Late night?
没有
No.
你别找韦尔比的麻烦了
Lay off that Welby guy.
不然呢?
Or you'll do what?
我把你妈妈牙踢进她肚子里去
Or I'll kick your fucking Momma's teeth in.
你才不会
No you won't.
谁跟你说我找他麻烦了?那个侏儒?
Who told ya I was laying on him anyway? The midget?
你他么说什么呢?
What the fuck are you talking about?!
我还他么想集中注意力查案呢 什么他么侏儒
I'm trying to fucking concentrate! Fucking midgets!
你到底在找什么啊?
What are you looking for, anyway?
这没什么好找的
There's nothing to look for.
我不知道牙怎么了
I don't know what it is.
感觉像是来回晃动
This feels like it's kinda waggling.
如果已经到晃动这种程度了 就得拔了
Well if it's waggling it's gonna have to come out.
你都不先看看怎么回事吗?
Ain't you gonna have a look at it first?
得拔牙了
It's gonna have to come out.
呃 能先给我打点麻药吗?
Uh, can I get a little Novocaine, there, Doc?
麻药几分钟后才有效
Give it a couple minutes.
我只想说 威廉•威洛比在这镇里
I just wanted to say... There's a lotta good friends
有很多朋友 海耶斯女士
of Bill Willoughby in this town, Mrs. Hayes,
不 啊 住手 疼死我了 上帝啊
No! Ouch! Stop it! No, god!
疼死我了
God damn it.
那你就跟威廉•威洛比的好朋友们说一声
Then why don't you tell those good friends of Bill Willoughby
让他们告诉威洛比做好他本职工作 好吗 肥狗?
to tell him to go do his fucking job, fat boy?
你好啊 米尔德里德
Hey there, Mildred!
今天你没碰巧去过牙医那 是吧?
You didn't happen to pay a visit to the dentist today, did ya?
- 没去过 - 什么?
- No. - Huh?
我说没去过
I Said 'No'.
哦 所以不是你在胖牙医杰弗里的胖拇指
Oh. So it wasn't you who drilled a little hole in one of
上钻了一个窟窿 是吗?
big fat Geoffrey's big fat thumbnails, no?
当然不是
Of course not.
- 你说啥? - 我说当然不是
- Huh. - I said "Of course not."
你在牙医身上钻了个窟窿?
You drilled a hole in the dentist?
不是 德尼斯 我没有
No, Denise, I didn't.
- 我也觉着挺有意思的 不过嘛
- Well, I thought it was kinda funny myself, but
他要起诉你 所以我恐怕要抓你回警局了
he wants to press charges, so we're gonna have to bring you in, I'm afraid.
你虐待黑鬼的伟大事业进展如何啊 迪克森?
So how's it all going in the nigger torturing business, Dixon?
是虐待有色人种 现在得这么称呼他们
It's 'Persons of color'-torturing business, these days,
如果你想知道的话
if you want to know.
我谁也没虐待
And I didn't torture nobody.
你脑子进水了吗 在电视上哔哔那些废话
What's the matter with you, saying that goddam stuff on TV.
我妈妈就看那电视节目
My momma watches that station!
你妈妈不知道你虐待嫌疑犯的事?
Your momma does not know about the torturing?
她什么也不知道 她反对这类事情
No she didn't know anything about it. She's against that kinda thing.
谁反对什么事?
Who's against what thing?
我妈妈 反对虐待有色人种这样的事
My momma. Is against 'Persons-of-color torturing'.
她说了虐待黑鬼 我跟她说不能再用"虐待黑鬼"这样的字眼
She said 'nigger-torturing'. I said you can't say 'nigger-torturing' no more.
得说是虐待有色人种
You gotta say 'Persons-of-color' torturing.
这才对吧 局长?
Isn't that right, Chief?
杰森 从这开始呢 我想海耶斯女士的案子就由我独自接管吧
I think I'll be able to take care of Mrs. Hayes on my own from here on, Jason.
好的 局长 我就呆在外面
Sure, Chief, I'll be right outside.
被这么看着我
Don't gimme that look.
如果因种族言论不当而开除警察的话
If you got rid of every cop with vaguely racist leanings then you'd have
那你就只能剩下三个警察了 而且他们都恨同性恋
three cops left and all of them are gonna hate the fags
所以 只能睁一只眼闭一只眼啦 你懂的
so what are ya gonna do, y'know
我想知道点事情 米尔德里德
I wanna know something, Mildred...
你为什么在可怜的胖杰弗里的拇指甲上
Why'd ya drill a hole thru
钻了一个洞?
poor fat Geoffrey's thumbnail?
那不是我干的
That didn't happen.
他手滑不小心给自己钻了个洞
His hand slipped and he drilled a hole thru his self.
他跟你说是我干的?
Did he say I did it?
看来我们各执一词啊 是不?
I guess it's just his word against mine, then huh?
就像所有听说过的强奸案一样
Kinda like in all those rape cases you hear about.
不过 这次可不一样
Except, this time,
作为女性涉案人的我是不会输的
the chick ain't losing.
这不是谁输谁赢的问题
It ain't really about winning or losing, though,
米尔德里德 是不是?
is it, Mildred?
我是说 你觉得我会在意你们谁输谁赢吗?
I mean, do you think I care about who wins or loses between the two of yous?
你觉得我会在意牙医吗?
Do you think I care about dentists?
我不在意牙医
I don't care about dentists.
没人在意牙医
Nobody cares about dentists!
我在意 或者
What I I do care about, or what I'm
我感兴趣的是
interested in,
你因此案牵扯在法院的时间这么长
is tying you up in court so long
导致你没多少时间在礼品店工作挣钱
that your hours at the gift shop be so shot to shit
这样的话 你就没有足够的钱去缴纳下个月广告牌的租金了
that you ain't got a penny to pay for another months billboards.
这才是我感兴趣的事情
That's what I'm interested in.
我还有点存款...
I got some dough put away...
可是我听说的是 你甚至不得不卖了你前夫的拖车
What I heard was you had to sell off your ex-husband's
来支付这个月的广告费 是吗?
tractor-trailer to even pay for this month's billboards, that right?
顺便问一下 老查理最近怎么样啊?
How is ole Charlie, by the way?
还在和那个在动物园工作的小实习生同居呢吗?
He still shacked up with that pretty little intern works down at the zoo?
他确实跟个一身骚味的女人同居
He's still shacked up with some chick who smells of shit.
我不知道这骚味是不是动物园里的动物留在她身上的
I don't know if the zoo's got anything to do with it.
不过我确实希望是动物留在她身上的
Although I'd hope so.
她多大?
How old is she?
19?真是明智啊
Nineteen? That's smart.
继续激怒我啊
Keep trying,
继续
Keep trying.
作为一个前警察
What's Charlie think about these here billboards of yours,
查理怎么看你这些广告牌?
an ex-cop like Charlie?
前警察 前家暴者 有什么区别呢?
Ex-cop, ex-wife-beater. Same difference, I guess, right?
但是你们两个各执一词 不对吗?
His word against yours, though, right?
查理不知道广告牌的存在 是不是?
Charlie don't know about them, does he?
这跟他没有关系
It's none of his business.
可是看起来是他在为广告牌买单啊
He's kinda paying for 'em though, ain't he?
是我在买单
I'm paying for 'em.
这个月是你 那
This month you are. How about when...
我不是故意要... 我知道...
- I didn't mean to... - I know...
- 我是不小心 - 我知道 小可怜
- It was an accident... - I know, baby.
是血
It's blood.
我去叫人
I'll go get somebody...
嘿!
Hey!
- 让她走吧 - 别这样局长
Just let her go. - C'mon Chief.
让她走!
Just let her go!
慢点 慢点 慢点
Easy, easy, easy.
嘿
Hey.
鸟会得癌症吗?
Do birds get cancer?
啊?小鸟 它们会得癌症吗?
- Huh? - Birds. Do they get cancer?
我不知道 但是狗会
I don't know. Dogs do.
好吧 我说的不是狗 是不是?
Yeah, well, I wasn't talking about dogs, was I?
真是"好"极了
Great.
又在回家的路上看见"惨遭奸杀"的标语了
The good old "Raped While Dying" route home.
假使我每天能有两秒钟可以不去想她
Cos if there was two seconds in a day when I didn't think about her,
或者不去想她是怎么死的
或者她怎么死的时候
and wasn't thinking about how she died, ".
你看 因为这广告牌 我又不得不想起这些来 是不是?
There ya go, think about it some more, why don't ya?"
广告牌的"好处"不止如此呢
It's good, too, that as much as a person might've
尽管我尽力避免知道案发时的细节
tried to avoid the details of what happened,
因为我知道这些细节不会有任何帮助 而且我心理也会承受不住
cos he didn't think it'd do any good, and he didn't think he could bear it,
但是她死去时的细节竟被人用20英尺的美化好的字体
it's also good to be informed in twenty-foot-high font and a real nice lettering,
登在广告牌上 让我每天都看得到 都不禁去想象那些画面
the precise details of her last moments.
她被强奸了还不够
That it wasn't enough that she was raped,
她死了还不够
and it wasn't enough that she died, no.
是"惨遭奸杀"
"Raped While Dying".
真是多谢你了妈妈
Thank you, mom.
我给过你尸检报告...
I gave you the police reports...
我没有看!
I didn't read 'em!
我已经够他妈伤心了
I'm depressed enough as it fucking is!
妈妈!
Mom!
什么事?
Yeah?
你今天晚上不出去吧?
You ain't going out again tonight, are ya?
丹妮丝和我会出去喝几杯
Denise and I are gonna grab a couple of beers, yeah.
丹妮丝载你去吗?
Denise gonna be driving ya?
安吉拉 你为什么不直接问我你是不是能借车?
Angela, why don't you just ask me if you can borrow the car?
我可以借你的车吗?不行
- Can I borrow the car? - No.
贱人!
Bitch!
如果你态度好点并且不叫我贱人的话
I'll give you money for a taxi
我会给你打车的钱的
if you ask me nice and don't call me a bitch.
如果你根本不打算借我为什么还让我问呢?
Why did you make me ask you borrow it if you was never gonna let me borrow it?
因为这很有趣 而且你整天都在抽大麻
Cos it was funny. And cos you've been smoking pot all day.
你真是个伪君子!- 伪君子?
- You are such a hypocrite! - Hypocrite?
- 对啊 - 为什么这么说?
Yeah. - How?
在我们小的时候你总是喝醉了载我们
You drove drunk with us in the car when we was kids.
你在胡说些什么?
What are you talking about?
爸爸告诉我的
Daddy told me.
你什么时候见他了?别转移话题
- When did you see him? - don't change the subject.
你有没有在我们小的时候喝醉了载我们?
Did you or did you not drive drunk with us in the car when we was kids?
只有一次 我想
Once. Maybe.
呵呵 对 就"一次"
Oh, "once", okay...
...在你爸爸快要把我打死的时候...
...when he was in the middle of beating the shit out of me...
我们只听了你的一面之词 不是吗?
Which we've only got your word about, right?
安吉拉 看在上帝的份上
Angela, For Christ's sake...
你为什么从来不站在我这边 罗比?
Oh why are you never on my side, Robbie?
在你不是婊子的时候我就会站在你这边了
I'm always on your side when you're not being a cunt.
- 嘿!- 嘿!
- Hey! - Hey!
这个家里不许再出现‘婊子’这样的词 你听懂了吗 年轻人?
There'll be no more 'Cunts' in this house, you got that, Mister?
那看来你要搬出去了?
What, are you moving out?
我开玩笑而已
It was a gag!
那你到底借不借给我车?
So are ya gonna let me borrow the car or what?
你怎么不走着去呢 安吉拉?
Why don't you just walk, Angela?
- 你怎么不走?- 你知道么?
- Why don't you just walk? - You know what,
我会走着去的
I will walk,
我会走的 你猜怎样?
I will walk. And y'know what?
我希望我在路上被人强奸
I hope I get raped on the way.
是吗?我也希望你在路上被强奸!
Yeah? Well I hope you get raped on the way too!
广告牌：怎么回事 威洛比局长？
我们要留你住院观察几天 威廉
We're gonna need to keep you in a few days, Bill.
咳血不是个好现象
You shouldn't be coughing up blood.
好吧 我也猜到了 医生
Yeah, I kinda guessed that, Doc.
我明天早上会再来的 我走了安妮
I'll swing by in the morning. Anne.
安妮
Anne.
看来我要去给你拿外套了
Guess I'll go get your coat, huh?
- 你知道我是不会呆在这的 - 我当然知道你不会
- Well you know I ain’t staying - You know I ain’t arguing
你这个老贱人
You... old... cunt.
我不老 罗比
I'm not old, Robbie.
是爸爸!
That's Dad!
嘿!爸爸!最近好吗?
Hey dad! How's it going?
那个疯女人在哪
Where's the crazy lady...?
这孩子头上都是该死的米花糖
The kid's got Rice fucking Krispies in his fucking hair!
这家里发生了什么事?
What's going on around here? And what the fuck's
还有那些该死的广告牌是什么意思?米尔德里德?
going on with these fucking billboards, Mildred?
- 我觉得意思挺明显的 不是吗?- 你为什么不亲自给我解释一下呢?
- Kinda self-explanatory, ain't it? - Well why don't you just explain it to me?
看来也没那么明显啊
Guess it ain't self-explanatory then.
好吧 我希望某些人专注于他们的工作
Well, y'know, I guess I wanted certain people's
仅此而已
minds kept on certain people's jobs, is all.
我他妈七个月都没有收到警察局关于案件的下文 但是你猜怎样
I hadn't heard a word from 'em in seven goddam months, but I tell ya this,
自从我挂起广告牌我就收到不少来自他们的反馈
I heard an awful lot from 'em since I put those billboards up
你觉得这会让他们专注破案?
You think this has focused their minds?
我告诉你他们会专注干什么
I'll tell you what it's focused their minds on. It's focused
他们会专注于玩死你
their minds on how exactly are they gonna fuck you up.
你越是把一个案件公之于众
The more you keep a case in the public eye,
这个案件被破解的可能性就越大
the better your chances of getting it solved,
这都是指南书里写的 查理
it's in all the guidebooks, Charlie.
这些广告牌花了多少钱?
How much those billboards cost?
大约一辆拖车的钱
Bout the same as a tractor-trailer.
- 你他妈笑什么?- 没什么
- What the fuck are you laughing at? - Nothing.
被一个脑袋里有麦片的家伙嘲笑!
Laughed at by a guy with fucking cereal in his hair!
佩内洛普怎么样?
How is Penelope?
- 啊?她还好 - 为什么不请她进来呢?
- Huh? She's alright. - Why don't you invite her in,
- 省得她坐在外面?- 她也来了?
- save leaving her sitting out there? - She's here?
- 她在车里 - 哦 这就说得通了
- She's out in the car. - Oh. That explains it.
- 说得通什么?- 我就知道我闻到了什么
- That explains what? - I knew I smelled something.
放开她
Let her go.
哦 我想用一下洗手间
Oh, um, I kinda needed to use the bathroom,
但是如果不太方便的话
but if it's inconvenient, actually
好像确实不太方便 是吧 我能看出来
it is inconvenient, isn't it, I can see it's
我可以等一下再去 没关系的...
inconvenient, I can hold it, it's alright...
穿过走廊第一个房间就是 你确定吗?
- It's the first door, down the hall. - Are you sure? I feel like I'm
- 感觉我好像打断了...- 快去尿你的!
- intruding... - Just go pee!
好的
OK.
听着 该说的你都说完了
Look, you've said what you came to say.
是吧?为什么不直接领着动物园小妞滚出我的房子呢?好吗?
Okay? Why don't ya just go get zoo girl and get the hell out of my house? Alright?
呃 实际上 动物园那边的事嘛...
Um, actually, zoo-wise,
很遗憾 他们现在开始裁人了
they were letting people go at the zoo, unfortunately,
显然裁人标准其中一条是"迟到最晚的人第一个被裁" 所以呢
and it was a case of "Last in, first out", so, yeah,
很不幸 因为这条我只能被动物园给裁了
unfortunately the zoo had to let me go.
但是马场那里在招人
But they were looking for people down at the horse-rides
去那里照顾残疾的马
for the disabled's, to look after the horses down there,
所以我现在在那工作
so I'm working down there now,
照顾残疾的马
looking after the disabled's horses,
一句话都别说
Don't say a word.
我没打算说
I wasn't gonna say a word.
难道我不希望这一切都没发生过吗?
You don't think I don't wish it had never happened?!
难道我不希望她还在世吗?
You don't think I don't wish she was still here
我知道你希望
I know you do.
我知道的
广告牌是不会让她起死回生的 米尔德里德
Billboards ain't gonna bring her back, Mildred.
总比你除了19岁小姑娘外什么也不"干"要有效 查理
Neither is fucking nineteen year olds, Charlie.
是的
Yeah.
但是我很清楚
But I know that.
快走吧
Just go.
好吧
Yeah, alright,
我就是个差劲老爸 你才是好妈妈
I'm such a shitty dad and you're such a great mom. Alright.
那为什么
So how come
她死之前的一周跑来问我
a week before she died she comes around asking
是不是能跟我一起住
if she can move in with me at my place,
因为她受不了你们每天辱骂对方
cos she couldn't stand the two of yous bitching at each other no more,
- 受不了你们总吵架- 我不相信你
- and fighting with each other no more.. - I don't believe you...
我说"不 呆在家里吧 你妈妈还是很爱你的"
And I said "No, stay at home, your mom loves you."
真希望我没说过这话
And now I wish I hadn't,
因为如果我没说的话她最起码还活着!
cos if I hadn't she'd still fucking be here!
- 我不相信你!- 你不信我?
- I don't believe you! - Don't believe me.
问问麦片小子吧
Ask Fruit Loop boy.
是真的吗?
Is it true?
我不知道 妈妈
I don't know, mom.
你知道的
Yeah, you do.
哦拜托
Oh come on
又是唐纳德•萨瑟兰!为什么 难道是什么该死的唐纳德•萨瑟兰季节吗?
Donald Sutherland again! What is this, a freaking Donald Sutherland season?!
我喜欢他
I like him.
我喜欢他的头发 头发
I like his hair. - Hair.
这是他女儿死的那段剧情
This is the one where his little girl dies.
在电影中总是那么吸引人
Always a plus in a movie!
说到死去的孩子
Talking of dead kids,
那位广告牌女士怎么样了
what's happening with the Billboard lady?
那个疯女人一句话都听不进去
Oh that cooze won't listen to reason.
简直是茅坑里的石头--又臭又硬
She's as tough as an old boot!
哦 你为什么不通过她的朋友搞垮她呢?
Oh. Why don't you just fuck her over thru her friends then?
- 啊 - 你知道的
- Huh. - Y'know,
你为什么不先搞垮她的朋友呢?通过这个方式让她认输
why don't you fuck her friends over? Bring her around out way.
她有没有你可以搞垮的朋友?
Has she got some friends you could fuck over?
关门 我进局子了 ——丹妮斯
混蛋
Bastard.
嘿白痴!
Hey fuckhead?!
- 什么?- 别说‘什么’迪克森
- What? - Don't say 'What', Dixon,
她都进来叫你白痴了 而且不许你
when she comes in calling you a fuckhead, and don't you come in here...
- 闭嘴!
- Shut up!
- 你!过来 - 不
- You! Get over here. - No.
你过来
You get over here.
好吧什么?别...迪克森!
- Alright... - What?! Don't... Dixon!
干什么?我在处理这件事!
What?! I'm taking care of this!
- 你不能允许一个公民在警局里叫你白痴!
- You do not allow a member of the public to call you a fuckhead in the station house!
这就是我正在做的事 实际上 我在用我自己的方式处理
That's what I'm doing, I'm taking care of it! In my own way. Actually.
现在快滚开!海耶斯夫人
Now get out of my ass! Mrs. Hayes.
请坐 有什么可以为你效劳的?
Grab a seat. What is it I can do for you today?
丹妮丝•沃森在哪?
Where's Denise Watson?
- 丹妮丝•沃森被逮捕了 - 什么罪名?
- Denise Watson's in the Clank. - On what charge?
- 非法持有 - 持有什么?
- Possession. - Of what?
两支大麻烟 量不少哦
Two marijuana cigarettes. Big ones.
- 保释听证会什么时候举行?- 我已经请求法官不让她被保释
- When's the bail hearing? - I asked the Judge not to give her bail
基于她之前持有大麻的记录 法官同意了
on account of her previous marijuana violations and the Judge said sure.
你这个该死的狗杂种
You fucking prick.
你不能在一个执法警官自己的警察局里
You do not call an officer of the law
叫他狗杂种 海耶斯夫人
a fucking prick in his own station-house, Mrs. Hayes.
事实上在哪里都不行
Or anywhere, actually.
你新采取的强硬措施是怎么回事 迪克森?
What's with the new hard-boiled attitude, Dixon?
是你妈妈教你的吗?
Your momma been coaching ya?
不 不是我妈妈教的
No. My momma doesn't do that.
把广告牌给我撤了
Take 'em down,
你听见了吗?
you hear me?
你处理的很好 迪克森
You did good, Dixon.
是的 我知道
Yeah, I know I did.
好了 规则有两部分
Now, the rules here are twofold;
无论何时你俩都不予许
no kid
离开这个摊子
can leave this goddam blanket at any goddam time,
并且每个娃娃和泰迪熊
and every single one of these dolls and these teddy bears
都必须连接在一起
has gotta be hooked up.
现在 你们妈妈和我
Now, your momma and I,
尽管看起来不像 但是我们还是会看到你们所有的小动作
although it won't look like it, we'll be watching every goddam move you make
在我们看着你们的时候 最重要的事情就是
and the most important thing while we're watching you
不要离开这个毯子
is you do not leave this blanket.
下一件最重要的事情是
The next most important thing is you do not
不许以任何方式
at any stage
让钓竿扎到你或者你姐姐的眼睛
allow the fishing rods to stick into you or your sister's eyeballs,
否则我们今天的"河边游玩钓鱼"行动就会失败
as this would be counter-productive to the entire operation.
我刚才怎么说的?
What would this be?
"河边游玩钓鱼"行动就会失败
Counterproductive to the entire operation.
那么士兵们...
Then troops...
开始钓鱼了
start fishing.
我们不能去"野战"
We. Are. Not.
可以的
We are.
嘿 宝贝
Hey, baby.
是的
Yeah!
还是没有抓到凶手
Still no arrests.
我也想知道是什么原因呢?
How come, I wonder?
因为上帝不复存在 世界都变得没有意义?
Cos there ain't no God and the whole world's empty
并且我们对彼此干什么都没有关系是吗?
and it don't matter what we do to each other?
哦我希望不是
Ooh, I hope not.
你是从哪里突然冒出来的 长得这么漂亮?
How comes you came up here outta nowhere, looking so pretty?
你不是想说服我相信有转生这回事吧 是吗?
You ain't trying to make me believe in reincarnation or something, are ya?
你很漂亮 但是你不是她
Well, you're pretty, but you ain't her.
她被杀害了
She got killed,
她将永远消失了
and now she's dead forever.
但是还是感谢你来
I do thank you for coming up, though.
如果我有食物的话我会给你的
If I had some food I'd give it ya,
但是我只有一些玉米片 形状太尖了 可能会害死你的
but I've only got some Doritos and It might kill ya, they're kinda pointy.
然后我们会去哪里呢?
Then where would we be?
哦 米尔德里德
Oh, Mildred.
是的 我
Yeah, so I
呃 刚巧在看我们当时签过的合同
uh, just happened to be looking over our contract we drew up
然后意识到
back that time, and what I realized was,
意识到尽管租金
I realized that although payment is to be made
需要在每个月的第一天支付
on the first day of each month,
但是你交的第一笔钱实际上是定金
the first payment you paid was actually a deposit,
不是吗 像我们说好的 实际上
wasn't it, like we said, so actually, in point of fact, you're actually
你已经拖欠租金
behind in your payments now, by,
一个多月了
yeah, a month.
是的 那是 呃
Yeah. That's, uh,
合同里写的 我仔细查看了一遍
what the contract says. Looking it over an' all.
律师也这样说
The lawyer says so too.
你什么时候需要下一笔租金 红发小子?
When do you need this next payment by, Red?
呃 实际上 现在就要
Uh, well, now, really.
或者...星...星期五?
Or... Fuh uh... Friday?
哇
Wow.
总要相信律师和广告商 是吧?
When you can't trust the lawyers and the advertising men,
不然美国会变成什么样了?
what the hell's America coming to, huh?
谁指使你的?
Who got to ya Red?
威洛比?
Willoughby?
- 没人指使我 - 快别扯了!
- Nobody got to me. - My fat fucking ass!
他要死了 米尔德里德
He's dying, Mildred.
我们都他妈要死了!
We're all fucking dying!
红发小子?
Red?
哦 嗨 帕梅拉 我们现在在忙
Oh, hi Pamela! Um, we're a little bit busy, at the moment,
帕姆 如果可以的话
Pam, if that's okay...
哦 红发小子 我知道
Oh Red, I know, and I know you were real anxious
我也知道你对要和海耶斯夫人谈话非常紧张什么的...
about talking to Mrs. Hayes this morning and all...
紧张?不
Anxious? No.
但是重点是 没必要紧张了 简直不敢相信!
But that's the thing, there's no need to be, cos you won't believe it!
一个墨西哥快递员刚来送了这个包裹
A little Mexican delivery boy just dropped in with this...
这是什么?
What the hell's this?!
- 我知道!是五千美金 而且你猜这字条怎么说?
- I know! It's five thousand dollars! And guess what
上面写着这是为了给海耶斯夫人付广告牌租金的
the note says? It says it's to pay for the rental on Mrs. Hayes's billboards!
你能相信吗?因为这我才打断你们的谈话
Can you believe it? That's why I butted in!
- 好吧 这是从哪寄过来的?- 上面没写
- Well, who's it from? - Well, it doesn't say.
那送包裹的人呢?
Well, where's the delivery boy?
他走了
Well, he went.
那你看见他是哪个公司的了吗?
- Well, did you see what company he was from?
- 没有 - 那他穿的是什么样的制服?
- Well, no. - Well, what kinda uniform did he have on?
他看起来就像那些胖胖的墨西哥男孩
Well, he just looked like one of those fat little Mexican boys.
骑着车子
On a bicycle
我做错什么了吗?- 没有 帕姆 你做的很好
Did I do something wrong? - No, Pam, you did good.
是的 帕姆 你做的真的很好
Yeah, Pam, you did real good.
是吗?太好了!
Did I? Great!
生活是不是很疯狂?
Ain't life crazy?
这纸条写的是什么?
What's the note say Red?
写着 呃
Says, er,
"这笔钱作为米尔德里德的广告牌租金基金
"This here money is to go towards the fund for Mildred Hayes's billboards,
因为她不是唯一一个恨警察的人
cos she ain't the only one round here who hates the pigs.
签署名 一个朋友"
Signed, a friend."
天哪 看来你不能对你的朋友太挑剔是吧?
Jeez, I guess ya can't be picky who your friends are these days, huh?
呃 看来你应该给我开张发票了 小子
Um, I guess I'll be needing a receipt off ya Red,
你知道的 写着下个月的租金一次付清的发票
y'know, saying the price of next month's is paid in full and all.
哦当然了 米尔德里德 当然了
Oh. Sure, Mildred, sure.
现在就要
Yeah. Like, now.
哦 当然可以
Oh! Sure!
妈妈喝醉了吗?爸爸?
Is mommy drunk, daddy?
不不 她只是有点偏头痛 仅此而已
No, no, she's just got a little migraine, that's all.
因为喝了夏敦埃酒
A little Chardonnay migraine,
你们俩不许再聊天了 好吗?
now no more chit chat out of you two, ok?
我们明天还可以不去上学吗?爸爸?
Can we stay home from school again tomorrow, daddy?
看看你妈妈明天早上怎么说吧 亲爱的...
We'll see what your mommy says in the morning, darling...
哦
Aww!
闭眼睛啦
Eyes close.
然后睡觉 好吗?
Then go to sleep, ok?
你闻起来不像刚吐过呢
You don't smell of puke.
是好迹象
Which is good.
用"水晶莹"牌牙膏 这是我的一个小技巧
Aquafresh. Trick I learned.
女人啊
Women, huh?
该你去马厩里打扫那些该死的马屎了 你知道么?
It's still your turn to clean the horseshit outta the stable, y'know?
那些该死的马!
Those fucking horses!
那是你的马!我要开枪打死那些该死的马!
They're your fucking horses! I'm gonna have those fucking horses shot!
让我来吧
I'll do it,
你个懒婆娘
you lazy bitch.
谢谢
Thank you, poppa.
今天真是美好的一天
That was a real nice day.
还有特别爽的一炮
And that was a real nice fuck.
你的活真的不错 威洛比先生
You got a real nice cock, Mr. Willoughby.
这是哪个剧的台词吧
Is that from a play,
我记得是"你的活真的不错 威洛比先生"
"You got a real nice cock, Mr. Willoughby?" I think.
我在某部莎士比亚的剧里听到过这句
I heard it in a Shakespeare one time.
你个笨蛋
You dummy.
是奥斯卡•王尔德的剧
It's Oscar Wilde.
"奥斯卡•王尔德"
"Oscar Wilde."
不要摘下头套 给警察打电话
我亲爱的安妮
My darling Anne.
在梳妆台的抽屉里还有封更长的信
There's a longer letter in the dresser drawer
我写了差不多一周
I've been writing for the last week or so.
那一封信 提到了我
That one covers us,
和我们的美好回忆
and my memories of us,
以及我是有多么爱你
and how much I've always loved you.
而这封信只提今晚
This one just covers tonight,
更重要的是 提提今天
and, more importantly, today.
今晚我去马厩结束了我的生命
Tonight I have gone out to the horses to end it.
我无法为我所做的行为道歉
I cannot say sorry for the act itself,
尽管我知道你会生我一段时间气
although I know that for a short time you will be angry at me
甚至因此而恨我
or even hate me for it.
但是请别
Please don't.
这不是什么"我独自来的这个世上
This is not a case of "I came in this world alone,
也将独自离开"之类愚蠢的话
and I'm going out of it alone" or anything dumb like that.
我可不是独自来到这个世上的 我妈当时也在
I did not come in this world alone, my mom was there,
我也不会独自离开
and I am not going out of it alone,
因为你也在
cos you are there,
你当时醉倒在沙发上
drunk on the couch,
讲着关于奥斯卡•王尔德的屌笑话
making Oscar Wilde cock jokes.
不 从某种意义上来讲 这是勇敢的原因
No. This is a case, in some senses, of bravery.
不是指一枪崩了自己的勇敢
Not the bravery of facing a bullet down;
接下来几个月的痛苦会愈来愈深
the next few months of pain would be far harder
远超开枪那瞬间的痛苦
than that small flash.
不 我说的勇敢是指权衡我余下日子的选择后所做的决定
No, it's the bravery of weighing up
是选择余下几个月的时间与你相伴
the next few months of still being with you,
能同你一起醒来
still waking up with you,
一起和孩子们玩耍
of playing with the kids,
还是选择余下的几个月里 我将从你们的眼中看到
against the next few months of seeing in your eyes
我的病痛给你们带来的折磨
how much my pain is killing you;
和你照顾我那日渐虚弱的身体
how my weakened body as it ebbs away
而这些会是你们对我最后的记忆
and you tend to it are your final and lasting memories of me.
我绝不会选择如此度过我的余生
I won't have that.
你们关于我最后的记忆会是我们一起在河边
Your final memories of me will be us at the riverside,
以及那愚蠢的钓鱼游戏
and that dumb fishing game
我觉得孩子们肯定作弊了
which I think they cheated at,
还有你我水乳交融 不分彼此
and me inside of you, and you on top of me,
几乎没有一点黑暗的
and barely a fleeting thought
念头闪过
of the darkness yet to come.
这就是最棒的了 安妮
That was the best, Anne.
一整天都没有去想我的病情
A whole day of not thinking about it.
宝贝 仔细回味这一天吧 因为这是我生命里最棒的一天
Dwell on this day, baby, cos it was the best day of my life.
替我吻吻女孩儿们
Kiss the girls for me,
记住我永远爱你们
and know that I've always loved you,
如果有天堂的话 我们再会吧
And maybe I'll see you again if there's another place.
如果没有
And if there ain't,
那我只能说 跟你在一起的日子是婉如天堂般的生活
well, it's been Heaven knowing you.
爱你的大男孩儿...
Your boy...
比尔
...Bill.
发生什么了?
What the Hell's going on around here?
怎么了?
What?
你现在能站住吗?
Can you stand now?
我能站住
Yeah,I can stand
我最好还是出去吧
I'd better get out there,
去安慰一下他们
say something to 'em.
你不会再头晕了吧?
You ain't gonna faint again, are ya?
背景音乐：His Master's Voice
我知道...现在最好的
I know... that the best thing,
也是唯一的
the only thing,
去纪念我们朋友的方法
to honor that man's memory right now,
就是去工作
is to go to work.
去成为一名
Is to be a
好警察
good cop.
去用他的方式思考
Is to walk in his shoes.
去做他生命里每天都在做的工作
Is to do what he did, every day of his life.
帮助他人
Help people.
这他妈的是怎么回事?
What the hell is going on?
你要去哪儿?
Where are you going?
你这头死猪!
You fucking pig!
你他妈在干什么?!
What the fuck are you doing?!
闭嘴!
Shut up!
看见了么 雷德?
See, Red?
我不光虐待黑人 白人也照虐不误..
I got issues with white folks too...
你他妈看什么看?
The fuck are you looking at?
播报昨天晚间发生的新闻 非常不幸
Reports, sadly, have come in overnight,
密苏里州艾宾镇的威廉•威洛比警长
that Chief William Willoughby of Ebbing, Missouri,
今天早晨在他的家中结束了自己的生命
took his own life early this morning in the grounds of his home.
加布里埃拉•福里斯特独家报道
This report just in from Gabriella Forrester.
悲剧突然降临到了这个位于
Tragedy came calling today upon this quiet family home
密苏里州艾宾镇郊外的平静家庭
outside of Ebbing, Missouri;
这个属于警长威廉•威洛比
a home belonging to Chief William Willoughby,
他的妻子安妮 以及他们两个小女儿 波莉和简共同的家庭
his wife, Anne, their two young daughters, Polly and Jane.
根据伤口显示
What appears to be a self-inflicted gunshot wound
威洛比警长是开枪自杀
brought life to an end for Chief Willoughby,
威洛比警长在艾宾镇备受尊敬
a man highly respected in Ebbing
他的勤劳 为社区的贡献 有目共睹
for his diligence and his service to the community,
目前尚不清楚是什么原因
What led him to take his life in the early hours of this morning
导致其开枪自杀
it is too early to speculate;
有传言是因为疾病缠身
there were rumors of illness;
也有传言称是工作压力太大
could it simply have been the pressure of the job;
还可能与我们两周前所报道一则关于广告牌的新闻有关
or could it have something to do with a story we ran here just two weeks ago,
一位名叫米尔德里德•海耶斯的女士
of these billboards, and the woman who put them there,
张贴的广告
...Mildred Hayes.
不要 不要
Don't. Don't.
你们好
Hey there.
你们知道是谁扔了那个罐头吗?
Do you know who threw that can?
什么罐头?
What can?
你呢 小甜心?你知道是谁扔的罐头吗?
How about you, sweetheart? Do you know who threw that can?
啊 不知道 我真没看到...
Uh, no, I didn't really see...
谢谢妈妈
Thank you mom.
先生 我能为你做些什么?
And what can I do for you today, Sir?
你叫什么名字?
What's your name?
名字就在我的牌子上 先生
Name's on my tag, man.
你有阅读障碍吗?
You hard of reading?
阅读障碍
Hard of reading
不 很好 "阅读障碍" 好像有点儿像"听觉障碍"
no, no. That's good, "hard of reading". It's kind of like "hard of hearing",
但实际上就是"阅读障碍"
but it's actually it's "hard of reading',
像是文字游戏什么的
it's like a play on words or something huh.
你想怎样?
What do you want?
啊 由于昨晚发生的不幸
Uh, I've been sent down to uh, take over from.
我被派来接替局长威洛比的职位
Chief Willoughby, in light of last night's unfortunate event.
你他妈是在逗我吧!
You have got to be fucking kidding me!
先生 你有文件证明吗?
Do you have any documentation to prove that, Sir?
你真想看我的证明文件吗 混蛋?
You really wanna see my documentation, fucker?
对 看看他的文件!
Yeah, see his documentation!
让他拿出来给你看看
Should make him show it to you.
你们这群白鬼混蛋 就没有人去工作吗?
None of you cracker motherfuckers got no work to do?
这不是种族歧视吗?
Ain't that racialist?
你的手怎么了 迪克森警官?
What happened to your hands, Officer Dixon?
哦 就是
Oh, I just kinda
把一个家伙从他妈的窗户里
banged 'em up a little bit while I was throwing
扔出去的时候受了点伤 你知道的
some guy out of a fucking window. Y'know,
- 日常工作 - 哦 是吗?
- the usual. - Oh yeah?
在警察学校 他们可从来没教过我这个
They never taught me that one at the Academy.
你读的是他妈什么学校?
Which fucking Academy you go to?
安吉拉•海耶斯的案子进展地怎么样了?
How's things coming along on the Angela Hayes case?
"关你屁事"的案子又进展地怎么样了?
How's things coming along on the 'Mind your own fucking business' case?
把你的枪和警徽交给我怎么样?
How things coming along on the hand me your gun and your badge?
- 哈? - 把你的枪和警徽交给我
- Huh? - Hand me your gun and your badge.
该死
Shit.
听着 我找不到我的警徽了
Hey, listen, I can't find my badge.
不 说真的 我可能已经弄丢了
No, seriously. Maybe I lost it
也可能是在把那家伙扔出去的时候掉在哪儿了
or dropped it when I was doing the window guy.
赶紧他妈的滚出我的警局
Just get the fuck out of my station house, man.
发生什么了?
What's going on?
我想我刚被解雇了
I think I just got fired.
被解雇还是停职 我也不确定是哪个...
Fired or suspended, I'm not sure which...
是被解雇了
Fired.
有什么需要的 给我说一声就行了
Anything I can help you with, just give me a holler.
我需要跟米尔德里德•海耶斯
Give Mildred Hayes
说一声
a holler.
可以啊
Okay.
你认识我?
You know me?
仅从电视和收音机里
Only from the TV,
了解过
and the radio.
这些写着"欢迎来到密苏里州"的兔子多少钱?
How much these here 'Welcome to Missouri' rabbits go for?
七块钱
Seven bucks.
上面不是写着么
It's writ right on 'em.
我想它现在不值七块钱了吧
Guess he ain't seven bucks now.
你为什么来这儿?
Why'd you coming here for?
我为什么来这儿?
What did I come in here for?
好吧 因为我是威洛比的好朋友 这么说如何?
Well, maybe I'm a good friend of Willoughby's, how about that?
你是吗?
Are you?
或者 是因为...
Or, y'know...
我是你女儿的朋友
maybe I was a friend of your daughter's or something.
这么说如何?
How about that?
你是吗?
Were you?
再或者 啊
Or, uh,
我是她快死的时候操她的那个人
y'know, maybe I was the guy who fucked her while she was dying?
这么说又如何?
How about that?
你是吗?
Were you?
不是
No.
但我希望我是
I would've liked to.
我在报纸上看过她的照片
I saw her picture in the paper there.
幸运得救 哈?
Saved by the bell, huh?
你打碎了我的兔子 欠我七块钱
You owe me seven fucking dollars for the rabbit.
等我下次路过的时候 你再向我要吧 米尔德里德?
Guess you'll have to get it off me next time I'm passing through, huh Mildred?
我想我会的
I guess I will.
你不知道我见到你有多高兴
You don't know how glad I am to see you.
- 什么? - 那个家伙想要恐吓我
- What?! - That guy was trying to scare me.
你可不那么容易被恐吓到啊
I wouldn't have said you scare easy.
反正不是最怂的
I ain't the worst.
我能为你做些什么 女士?
What can I do for you, ma'am?
这是昨天晚上我丈夫自杀前留给你的
My husband left this for you before he shot himself in the head last night.
- 我很抱歉 威洛比太太... - 是吗?
- I'm sorry, Mrs. Willoughby... - Are you?
你真的很抱歉?
Are you really?
我当然是
Sure I am.
当然是你最希望看到的结局 是不是?
Surely it's the perfect ending for you, isn't it?
这就是证明
It's proof
你的那三块广告牌 已经成功了
that they've been successful, these billboards
不是吗?换来了一个警察的死
of yours, isn't it, a dead policeman?
多值啊
It's quantifiable now.
- 你在为此指责我吗? - 不
- Are you blaming this on me? - No.
我不是在指责你 我只是来给你这封信
I'm not blaming this on you. I just came to give you the letter.
我的两个小女儿还在外面车里
Now, my two little girls are out in the car,
我不能待在这儿和你聊天了
so I'd better not stay and chat.
我不知道今天我们该做些什么
I'm not quite sure what we're going to do for the rest of the day.
真的很难知道
It's hard to know what to do
你丈夫自杀那天该做什么
the day your husband kills himself.
真的很难知道
It's hard to know what to do.
亲爱的米尔德里德
Dear Mildred,
或许你看到这封信时 我已经死了
Dead Man Willoughby here.
首先 我想向你道歉 还没抓到
Firstly I wanted to apologize for dying
杀你女儿的凶手我就死了
without catching your daughter's killer.
这对我来说是巨大的痛苦
It's a source of great pain to me, and it would
并且一想到你认为我不在乎这个案子 我就十分心痛
break my heart to think you thought I didn't care,
因为我很在乎
cos I did care.
确实有一些案子...
There are just some cases...
你永远也找不到突破口
...where you never catch a break,
接着五年过去了
then five years down the line
人们听到有个家伙在某个酒吧或是牢房里
some guy hears some other guy bragging about it in a bar-room
吹嘘这件事儿
or a jail-cell
然后整个事情就这么被一种十分愚蠢的方式解决了
and the whole thing is wrapped up through sheer stupidity.
我希望安吉拉的案子也能如此 我真的希望
I hope that might be true for Angela, I really do.
其次
Second,
我必须得承认 米尔德里德 广告牌真他妈是个好主意
I gotta admit, Mildred, the billboards were a great fucking idea.
就像走了一步棋一样
They were like a chess move.
虽然和我的死一点关系都没有
And although they had absolutely nothing to do with my dying,
但是我敢肯定 镇上的人都会认为我的死和广告牌有关
I'm sure that everyone in town will assume that they did,
认为这是威洛比作为回击的一步棋
which is why, for Willoughby's counter-move,
我替你付了广告牌下个月的租费
I decided to pay the next month's rent on 'em.
我觉得这很有趣
I thought it'd be funny,
在我被安葬之后你还得维护他们一个月
you having to defend 'em a whole another month after they've stuck me in the ground.
跟你开个玩笑 米尔德里德 哈哈
The joke is on you, Mildred, ha ha,
我希望他们不会杀了你
and I hope they do not kill you.
那么祝你好运 所有的事情都好运
So good luck with all that, and good luck with everything else too.
我希望并且祈祷你能抓住凶手
I hope and I pray that you get him.
你想我去和他们谈谈吗?
Well, do you want me to go down and talk to them?
不 我不想你去和他们谈
No I don't want you to go down and talk to them.
某人把他妈自己的母亲送去和他妈的警察聊天
Somebody sending their goddam mother down to talk to the goddam police.
然后说什么?
And say what?
说让你回去工作
And say to give you your job back.
再把那个黑人干掉
And to get rid of the black guy.
他们才不会听某人母亲的话
They ain't gonna listen to some guy's mother,
就去干掉某个黑人
asking them to get rid of some black guy.
事情已经发生了
Things have moved on in The South.
但事情不应该发生!
Well it shouldn't've!
他们会给你一些辞退费吗?
Will they give you some money for being laid off and all?
我可不知道把人扔出窗户
I don't know what the compensation scheme is
还能得到什么补偿 妈妈
for when you throw a guy out of a window, Mom.
我得提前查一下 让我谷歌一下
I guess I shoulda looked into that beforehand. Let me Google that.
也许会有几千块?
A couple grand, maybe?
你在那儿工作三年了
You've been there three years.
还不算在警校待的五年
Not counting the five years at the Academy.
是六年!
Six!
如果算上留级那一年的话
If you count the year you were held back.
- 你要去哪儿? - 不关你的事
- Where ya going? - None of your business.
去见你的漂亮姑娘?
Off to see your fancy woman?
- 我没有漂亮姑娘 - 是的 我知道
- I don't got a fancy woman. - Yeah. I know.
- 嘿 你最好小心点儿 - 不然你就怎么样?
- Hey, You wanna watch yourself. - Or you'll do what?
我就把你头打爆
I'm blowin' your goddam head off.
- 你听说那个新闻了吗? - 什么新闻?
- Oh, did you hear the news? - What news?
今天早上迪克森把韦尔比扔到窗户外面了
That Dixon guy threw that Welby guy out his window this morning.
你是在逗我吧
You're shitting me.
他还好吗?
Is he okay?
这是在逗我吧!
You're shitting me!
哦!天啊!
Woah! Shit!
我的天啊!
Holy Shit!
操!
Fuck!
去家里再拿一个灭火器!
Go get the other one from the house!
我不应该先给消防局打电话吗?
Shouldn't I call the fire department?
去他妈的消防局!可能就是他们放的火!
Fuck the fire department! They probably started it!
好吧 别做傻事!
Well don't do anything stupid!
卑鄙 卑鄙 卑鄙 真他妈的卑鄙!
Scumbags, scumbags, scumbags. Fucking scumbags!
该死!
Shit!
好吧
Alright.
你是在逗我吗?
Are you kidding me?
妈 你在干什么?
Mom, What the hell are you doing?
好的 快来...
Okay, Alright. Come on...
别管了 妈 拜托 已经太迟了
Leave it, Ma. Please. It's too late.
- 松手 罗比 - 妈 拜托 别管了!
- Robbie. - Mom, leave it, please!
松手 罗比!
Robbie!
手怎么样了?
How are those hands?
给我们一分钟
Give us a minute.
我能问你几个问题吗?
May I ask you a couple questions?
你问什么都行 制服我逮捕我都行
You can ask me all the questions you want, take me down and arrest me.
我不会逮捕你 海耶斯太太 我没理由逮捕你
I'm not gonna arrest you, Mrs. Hayes. I got nothing to arrest you for.
现在没有而已
Not yet you ain't.
我们并不都是你的敌人 明白吗?
We ain't all the enemy, y'know?
我要折磨死那群混蛋
I'll crucify the motherfuckers.
你要做什么 米尔德里德?
What are you gonna do to 'em, Mildred?
你要折磨死他们?
You're gonna crucify 'em?
是的 我要折磨死他们
Yeah, I'm gonna crucify 'em.
你要折磨谁?
Who you gonna crucify?
那群混蛋?
The motherfuckers?
对!
Yeah!
我要折磨死那群混蛋
I'm gonna crucify the motherfuckers.
好吧 那这些混蛋最好要小点心了
Well, then those motherfuckers better watch out,
啊?
huh?
好极了
Fucking A.
这他妈是怎么了?
What's this shit...?
...可能目睹了广告牌被烧之后心痛不已
...and as sad as the spectacle of these burned out billboards might be,
由于威洛比警长的去世
in light of the death of Chief Willoughby,
人们不禁会去想这个发生在艾宾镇郊外的
this reporter for one can't help but wonder whether this finally puts an end
三块广告牌的奇闻会不会就此结束...
to the strange saga of the three billboards outside of Eb...
这当然不会结束 你个傻子
This don't put an end to shit, you fucking retard,
好戏才刚刚开始
this is just the fucking start,
把这些在你的"早安密苏里他妈的起床播报"里播出去 婊子!
so why don't you put that on your "Good Morning Missouri fucking Wake-Up Broadcast", bitch!
我看电视上说昨晚镇子郊区失火了
I see on the TV there was a buncha fires lit outside o' town last night.
失火了?
Buncha fires, huh?
就在那些广告牌那儿
Out at those billboards.
好吧 如果我还是警察 我可能还会对谁放的火感兴趣
Yeah, well, back when I was a cop I woulda been interested in who set those fires
因为 专业点讲 这肯定是人为纵火
cos, technically, that's arson,
不过鉴于他们已经不再雇我了
but as I am no longer employed by those people
我真的他妈的一点都不关心
I don't really give a good god damn, now do I?
这里是迪克森家
The Dixon residence.
嘿 迪克森 是我 塞德里克
Hey Dixon. It's me, Cedric.
嘿 警官
Hey, Sarge.
- 你有消息了吗? - 关于什么的?
- You got any news? - News about what?
我不知道
I don't know,
关于我工作之类的事儿?
about my job and stuff?
不 不 什么?
No, no. What?
不
No.
安妮•威洛比刚刚来送了一封信
Anne Willoughby just dropped in a letter
是比尔生前写给你的
that Bill wrote you before he died.
我的天!上面怎么说?
Oh my God! What's it say?
我还没看 迪克森 这又不是给我的信
I haven't read it, Dixon, it's not my letter.
哦 听着 我现在就过去...
Oh. Listen, I'll come right down...
差不多15分钟就到
I'll be there in like 15 minutes.
好吧 呃...就目前现状而言
Well, uh... I don't think that'd be such a great idea,
我不认为这是个好主意 杰森
as things stand, Jason.
你那儿还有警局的钥匙 对吧?
Uh, you've still got your keys to the station-house though, right?
对
Yeah.
好的 那你等大家都离开了再过来拿走如何
Well, why don't you just come pick it up when everyone's gone home.
我可以把它留在你桌子上
I can leave it on your desk for ya.
哦 好的
Oh. Okay.
事实上
Actually, yeah,
你把信拿走后
then when you're done you can
顺便把钥匙留下
just leave the keys,
省得我们之后再去找你要
save us picking 'em up later.
好的
Alright.
背景音乐：Last Rose of Summer (Thomas Moore)
杰森 是我威洛比
Jason, Willoughby here.
很抱歉 我现在已经死了
I'm dead now, sorry about that,
但我还有一些话想对你说
but there's something I wanted to say to you
一些生前从未说过的话
that I never really said when I was alive.
我觉得你拥有成为一名好警察的资质 杰森
I think you've got the makings of being a really good cop, Jason,
你知道为什么吗?
and you know why?
因为 在内心深处
Because, deep down,
你是一个正直的人
you're a decent man.
你知道你不会觉得我会这么想 但我就是这么想的 笨蛋
I know you don't think I think that, but I do, Dipshit.
不过 我也觉得你太容易生气了...
I do think you're too angry, though,..
我知道这都是归因于你父亲的去世
And I know it's all since your dad died and
你不得不照料你的妈妈和一切...
you had to go look after your Mom and all...
但是只要你还把这么多仇恨深埋在心底
But as long as you hold onto so much hate
我觉得你就永远不会成为...
then I don't think you're ever going to become...
那个我所知道 也是你想成为的
What I know you wanna become...
一名警探
A Detective.
因为你很清楚自己需要什么才能成为一名警探
Cos you know what you need to become a detective.
我知道在我说这些的时候你会惊讶
And I know you're gonna wince when I say this...
但你成为一名警探 所真正需要的 其实...
But what you need to become a detective...
是爱
is Love.
去他妈的!
Fuck 'em!
因为只有通过爱才能达到内心的平静
Because through Love comes Calm,
而通过内心的平静才能思考
and through Calm comes Thought.
有些时候 你需要思考才能解决案子 杰森
And you need Thought to detect stuff sometimes, Jason.
你需要的仅此而已
It's kinda all you need.
你甚至连枪都不需要
You don't even need a gun.
仇恨也绝对帮不上你什么忙
And you definitely don't need Hate.
恨永远解决不了问题
Hate never solved nothing...
但是冷静却不一样
But Calm did.
思考也很有帮助 试试吧
And Thought did. Try it.
试着改变一下
Try it just for a change.
没人会把你当成同性恋
No-one'll think you're gay.
如果他们真这么觉得 那就逮捕这些恐同的家伙
And if they do, arrest 'em for homophobia!
给他们个措手不及!
Won't they be surprised!
祝你好运 杰森
Good luck to you, Jason.
你是一个好人
You're a decent man,
你这段时间运气一直很糟
and yeah you've had a run of bad luck...
但事情会有转机的
But things are gonna change for you...
我能感觉到
I can feel it.
冷静
Calm.
千万别慌
你们看见什么了?
So what did you see?
当我们从喷泉那儿转弯的时候
Well when we turned the corner from Spring,
火已经烧的很大了
the fire was already raging,
之后
and then
两分钟之后一位警官从窗户上跳了出来
two seconds later the cop guy just jumps out the window...
等一下
Wait.
你们两个从喷泉那里转的弯?
The two of you turned the corner from Spring?
- 你们之前在哪儿?- 就在我的住处周围闲逛
- Where were you before this? - Round at my place.
你们两个是男女朋友的关系?
You two are boyfriend and girlfriend?
刚确立关系不久
Well, it's early stages, y'know.
他说的对吗?
Is that right?
我们约过几次
We've had a couple dates.
那你下周肯赏脸一起跟我共进晚餐吗?
So you wanna go out to dinner next week?
好吧 我答应跟你去
I'll go out to dinner with ya.
但我不会跟你上床
But I ain't gonna fuck ya.
你说啥?我也不想上你
what? I ain't gonna fuck you neither.
可能吧
I guess.
他是烧伤患者
Burn victim.
已经服了不少镇定剂了
He's pretty heavily sedated.
你怎么样了 兄弟?
Hey man?
天啊 你还好吗?
You doing okay? Jeez,
你烧的非常严重
you got burned up pretty bad.
但是你会好起来的
You'll be okay though.
你想要一杯橙汁吗?
You want a glass of orange juice?
我找到了一根吸管
I got a straw somewhere...
嗨
Hey.
别哭啊
Don't cry.
你会好起来的
You'll be okay.
对不起 韦尔比
I'm sorry, Welby.
你认识我? 真的对不起
- You know me? - I'm sorry.
为什么事情道歉?
Sorry for what?
我把你从窗户上扔出去了
For throwing you out the window.
- 对不起 - 道歉没用
- I'm sorry man. - I don't care.
别他妈哭了
And stop fucking crying.
泪水里的盐分会让你烧伤部位恶化的
The salt'll just fuck up your wounds.
我还以为盐分对伤有好处呢
I thought salt was supposed to be good for wounds.
我他妈的也不是医生啊
Well what am I, a fucking doctor?!
谁啊
Who is it?
哦 你不认识我的
Oh you don't know me really.
那你想干什么?
Well what do you want?
我是为那广告牌来的
I come about the billboards.
广告牌怎么了?
What about 'em?
它们烧毁了
They got burned up.
我知道啊
I know that.
我是其中一位布置广告牌的人
I'm one of the guys who put the 'em up in the first place.
杰罗姆
Jerome.
您有何贵干?
What can I do for ya, Jerome?
你知道吗 要张贴那么大尺寸的海报时
Well, y'know, when you're putting up a buncha posters like that,
要小心它们会折损
为了防止海报损坏或者被人撕了
just in case any of 'em gets screwed up or torn,
他们给了你很多复印件 对吧?
they give ya a set of duplicates, y'know?
不 我对这件事一无所知
No, I didn't know that.
梯子很结实 詹姆斯
Ladder's pretty steady as it is, there, James.
那不错啊 我喜欢做扶梯子的活儿
Oh, that's okay. I like holding ladders.
我都要不认识我自己了
It takes me out of myself.
-需要帮忙吗?-嗨
- Need a hand? - Hey.
- 你什么时候出来的? - 刚出来一个小时
- When'd you get out? - An hour ago.
法官投了否决票 他承认逮捕报告还没有完善
Judge threw it out, said the arrest report weren't filled out right.
所以说你..
Say, you.
你没有烧了警察局吧?
Say, you didn't burn down the police station, did ya?
她没有 我和她整晚呆在一起
No. She was with me the whole night.
- 一言难尽啊 - 好吧
- It's a long story. - Okay.
- 嗯 - 嗨
- Okay. - Hey.
嗨
Hey.
你确定要贴威洛比的这个?他不是已经死了?
You sure you still wanna put up the Willoughby one, him dead an' all?
为什么不贴呢?广告费都是他付的
Why not? He paid for it.
确实是啊
True.
看 是那个混账东西
Look, this fucking asshole.
我们还是来这儿了
Well, here we are
对啊 我们来了
here we are.
我喜欢带奶酪的菜
I like cheesy things.
我要点一些奶酪类的菜
I'm gonna look for cheesy things.
好吧
Alright.
那是谁啊?
Who's that?
我的前夫
My ex-husband.
和他十九岁的女朋友
And his nineteen year old girlfriend.
- 你想走吗? - 不必了
- You wanna leave? - No, no.
我们这是说好的
A deal's a deal.
这也太疯狂了 兄弟
It was fucking wild, man,
我想我以前肯定是疯了
I think I was certifiably fucking insane for a while back there.
什么时候?
When was this?
大约九 十个月之前吧
Bout nine, ten months ago.
-你是一个人去的吗?-不，我和几个兄弟一起
- Were you on your own or what? - No, had a couple buddies with me.
-是吗? -对啊
- Oh yeah? - Yeah.
他们也上她了?
They fuck her too?
我想他们视奸就够了 你懂的
I think they got their kicks just watching, you know.
- 是吗 - 对啊
- Uhuh. Yeah? - Yeah.
她性感吗?
Was she hot?
用汽油布给她弄晕了之后 她才算是性感
After the gasoline kicked in she was hot.
背景音乐：Blessed Are
晕倒后的她让我上她的欲望更强烈
That's when I really wanted to fuck her even more.
我都不知道这股邪火我能不能给消掉
I don't know if I could get that out of my mind.
我才不会因为这事被抓呢 在那的最后一天...
I ain't going down for that shit, last fucking day down there...
他一直在那儿吗?
He been there the whole time?
谁啊?
Who?
脸被烧的那个乡巴佬 他妈的一直在那儿走来走去
Burnt-face-Jake. Keeps fucking walking up and down.
我不知道啊 应该没有吧
I don't know. I don't think so.
- 再喝一杯 - 好啊
- Another round. - Yeah.
八美元
Eight bucks.
马埃斯托（酒名）
Maestro.
伙计 有什么事么?
Can I help you with something, man?
你说什么
Excuse Me?
你一整晚在这儿晃过来晃过去的
You've been looking over here all fucking night,
如果你没什么想跟我说的话
now, unless you got something to say to me,
你最好还是跟你那张烧伤鬼脸一起从我眼前消失吧
why don't you take your burnt fucking face and get the fuck outta here, okay?
你要干什么?
What are you doing?
- 你要干什么? - 等等等等等
- What are you doing? - Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait...
相信我好吗?
Just trust me, okay?
你喜欢魔法吗?
You like magic?
- 你要相信我 - 要变戏法就赶紧变
- Just trust me... - Just do the fucking trick.
好的
Okay.
搞什么鬼
What the fuck?
嗨
Hey.
嗨!
Hey!
- 嗨!够了! - 这跟你有什么关系?
- Hey! That's enough now! - What's it to ya, fucker?
- 这个人是警察 他是警察! - 这个人是警察!他是警察!
- The guy's a cop man! He's a cop! - The guy's a cop man! He's a cop!
是吗?他没有戴警徽啊
Oh yeah?He ain't wearing no badge.
我把我的警徽给搞丢了
I lost my badge.
我记不得我在哪儿把他弄丢了
I can't remember where I lost it.
是你挑起来的
You started this, man!
我可他妈的没动你
I didn't do shit to you.
我知道是我挑的事 我把你的脸抓花了
I know I started it. I scratched you up like a bitch.
你他妈的
你他妈倒是挺明白啊
That's exactly fucking right...
我去一下洗手间
Gotta use the little boys' room.
- 你想对我说些什么吗?
- You got something to say to me?
早知道你跟他来一起的话 我就跟你们拼桌一起吃了
If I had known, we could've double-dated.
你那傻女友没有限制你工作日夜晚的回家时间吗?
Doesn't shitgirl have a curfew weeknights?
没 没有 我一会儿准备带她去看马戏团表演
No, no, in fact I was actually gonna take her to the circus later,
但是现在我看没必要了 你的小侏儒会玩杂耍吗?
but there's no need now. Does he juggle?
听好 我跟他只吃这一次饭 因为他之前帮过我 明白了吗?
Look I'm having one dinner with the guy cos he did me a favor, okay?
你不用因为跟一个侏儒约会
You don't have to explain yourself to me cos
而跟我解释什么 米尔德里德
you're having dinner with a midget, Mildred.
- 我不是在向你解释 - 在我看来 你就是
- I'm not explaining myself to you. - You kinda are.
听着 我不想扫你的兴
Look, I didn't come over to break your balls,
你想约多少侏儒都随你
you can date as many midgets as you want.
不
No,
我过来是想说 我很抱歉
I came over to say I was sorry, actually.
为啥抱歉?
Sorry for what?
我对你的广告牌以及发生的所有事抱歉
I'm sorry about what happened to your billboards and all.
好吧
Yeah well,
都已经过去啦  - 好吧
that's all water under the bridge now, I guess. - Good
我很开心 我当时喝醉了 但这不是借口
I'm glad. I was pretty drunk, but it still don't excuse it.
所有的这些愤怒
All this anger, man,
佩内洛普那天告诉我
Penelope said to me the other day,
愤怒不得宣泄只能酝酿出更深的愤怒
it just begets greater anger,
你知道吗?
y'know?
她说的没错
And it's true.
"酝酿"这词是佩内洛普说的?
Penelope said 'Begets'?
是的
Yeah,
愤怒不得宣泄只能酝酿出更深的愤怒
'It begets greater anger'.
你照顾好这位小女人 行吗?
You take care of this little lady, okay sport?
对你来说 是大女人 对吧?
Big lady, compared to you, right?
- 你还好吧?- 我现在想回家了
- You alright? - I think I'd like to go home now.
别烦我好吗 詹姆斯 我们下次再约好吗?
Don't gimme any shit, James? We can do this another time, alright?
我为什么还要跟你约会呢? 从进饭店开始
Why would I wanna do this another time? You've been
你一直是一副尴尬的样子
embarrassed to be here ever since we arrived.
- 你可别这么说行么
- Oh for Christ's sakes,
我没有强迫你来约会
I didn't force you to come on this date,
好吧?你强迫我来的
alright? You forced me.
强迫你?
Forced you?
我约你出来
I asked you on a date.
哇哦 你真行 你知道吗?
Wow! Well, y'know,
我明白的
I know
我知道你瞧不起我 对吧?
I ain't much of a catch, okay?
我知道我只是个卖二手车的矮子 还酗酒 这我都知道
I know I'm a dwarf who sells used cars and has a drinking problem, I know that.
但是 你又是谁啊?
But who the hell are you, man?
你不过就是个敢登反警察广告的苦情女人而已
You're that Billboard Lady who never ever smiles,
从没见你对谁说过什么中听的话
who never has a good word to say about anybody,
还在那天晚上放火烧了警察局!
and who, in the evening times, SETS FUCKING FIRE TO POLICE STATIONS!
你这样的人居然有资格瞧不起我?!
And I'm the one who's not a catch?!
喂!
Hey!
你知道吗 我本不必来也不用帮你扶梯子!
Y'know I didn't have to come and hold your ladder!
别闹事了
Now don't make a scene.
你真的对他说"愤怒不得宣泄只能酝酿出更深的愤怒"?
Did you really tell him "Anger begets greater anger"?
哦!是的!
Oh! Yes!
是我!但那不是我自己编的
I did! I didn't make it up myself though.
我可编不出这么高级的话 我是在书签上看到这句话的
I can't claim  that! No, I read it on a bookmark.
那书签就在我最近看的一本书里
Which was in a book I was reading.
关于保罗奥的
About polio.
还是保罗 不记得了 那位骑马的叫什么?保罗奥?
Polo. No, which is the one with the horses? Polio?
- 是保罗吧 - 保罗
- Polo - Polo.
对她好点 查理
Be nice to her, Charlie.
明白了吗?
You got that?
杰森!
Jason!
别管我 别看我 妈妈
Just leave me, don't look at me, Momma.
你...
You..
不要!不要!
No! Do not!
不要
Don't.
开门!
Open up this door!
求你了 杰森!
Please, Jason.
让我帮你
I'll help you.
求你了 开门
Please, open the door.
求你了
Please.
求你了 开门
Please, open the door.
开门!
Open up!
杰森!
Jason!
我没事 妈妈
I'm alright, Momma.
一切都会好起来的
It's all gonna be alright.
希望你不要抱太高期望 但是有个人
I don't wanna get your hopes up, alright, but there's a guy,
我觉得他可能是作案人
and I think he might be the guy.
我拿到了他的DNA
I got his DNA.
足够多的DNA
I got a lot of it, actually.
- 这会儿警方正在检查  - 有没有把他关押起来?
They're making the checks as we speak. - He's in jail?
没有 但是找到他不难
No, but he ain't gonna be hard to find.
为什么你觉得他就是作案人?
Why do you think he's the guy?
我听他说 在去年年中的时候
I heard him talking about something that he did to a girl
他对一个女孩下了手
in the middle of last year.
我没听完 但是
I couldn't hear all of it, but
听起来很像安吉拉那件案子
it sounded a lot like what happened to Angela.
他把我暴打了一顿
Then he beat the crap outta me.
但正好
But cos of that
我拿到了他很多DNA
I got a bunch of his DNA.
所以 我想
So I wanted
早点让你知道 我不想让你放弃希望 知道吗?
to let you know sooner rather than later. I didn't want you to give up hope, y'know?
我尽量吧
I've been trying not to.
就像我妈妈说的 你能做的就是不断尝试
Well, all you can do is try, as my Momma says.
不管有多少希望...
Not so much about hope as about...
我之前
well, I didn't used to be
在学校英语学得不好
very good at English at school,
原话大概是"你能做的就是不断努力..
so it was more "All you can do is try...
学好英语"
to not be so crap at English."
如果你想当警察 你的英语要好呀
Cos you need English, really, if you wanna be a cop.
如果你想做任何事
If you wanna be anything.
真的
Really.
除非你打算去墨西哥住了
Unless you live in Mexico or something.
但谁想住在墨西哥啊?
But who wants that?
嘿 迪克森
Hey, Dixon.
谢谢你!
Thank you!
你干得好 杰森
You did good, Jason.
你干得真的棒
You did real good.
但他不是嫌疑人
But he wasn't the guy.
什么?
What?
DNA不匹配
There was no match to the DNA,
与同类型的其他案子也不匹配
no matches to any other crimes of this nature,
事实上与任何案子都不匹配
to any crimes at all, in fact.
他的没有案底
And his record is clean.
也许他只是在吹牛
Maybe he was just bragging.
他不可能只是吹牛而已
He wasn't just bragging.
也许是吧 但是安吉拉死的的时候
Well, that's as may be. But at the time of Angela's death
他都不在国内
he wasn't even in the country.
他在哪里?
Where was he?
我已经看了他出入境的记录了
But I've seen his records of entry and exit to the States,
我和他长官谈过了
and I've spoken to his Commanding Officer.
他不在国内 迪克森
He wasn't in the country, Dixon.
他不是我们要找的人
He ain't our guy.
不 他...
No, he ..
他也许不是我们要找的人 但是他一定犯了事  - 我知道他犯了
He might not be our guy, but he still done something shitty. - I know he did.
不在密苏里州
Not in Missouri he didn't.
他当时人在哪?
Where was he?
这个是机密信息
That's classified information.
得了
Come on, man.
如果这个人要接受一位部队指挥官的命令
If the guy's got a Commanding Officer,
如果这个人九个月前刚回国
and if the guy got back to the country nine months ago,
如果不能透露他去过的那个国家
and if the country where he was is classified,
那你觉得他是去了哪个国家?
which country do you think he was in?
你知道...
Hey, you know ..
我给你点提示
I'll give you a clue.
有沙漠
It was sandy.
这并不能真正缩小它的范围
That doesn't really narrow it down.
你需要知道就是
All you need to know is,
他没有做什么有关安吉拉海斯的事
he didn't do nothing to Angela Hayes.
我们将接着找
So we're gonna keep looking.
好吗?
Alright?
我终于找到我的警徽了
I found my badge after all.
有人吗?
Hello?
我是迪克森
It's Dixon.
说吧
Tell me.
他不是作案人
He wasn't the guy.
米尔德丽德?
Mildred?
你确定吗?
Are you're sure?
案发的时候他不在国内
He, um, he wasn't even in the country when it happened.
所以 不管怎么说
So, whatever he did,
他都不可能作案
he didn't do it round here.
抱歉 我又让你失望了
I'm sorry I got your hopes up.
没事
It's alright.
至少我这一天充满了希望 比我之前的情况好很多了
At least I had a day of hoping. Which is more than I've had for a while.
我有事要挂电话了
I'd better go.
有件事
There was
我在想一件事
there was one thing I was thinking.
什么事?
What's that?
他不是这个案子的强奸犯
Well... I know he isn't your rapist.
他却是其他案子的强奸犯
He is a rapist, though.
我很肯定
I'm sure of that.
你跟我说这些是什么意思?
What are you saying to me?
我有他的车牌
I got his license plate.
我知道他住在哪里
I know where he lives.
他住哪里?
Where's he live?
他住在爱达荷州
Lives in Idaho.
有点意思
That's funny.
我明早开车去爱达荷州
I'm driving to Idaho in the morning.
需要伴儿吗?
Want some company?
当然
Sure.
背景音乐：Buckskin Stallion Blues
喂 迪克森
Hey, Dixon.
什么?
Yeah?
我要告诉你件事
I need to tell you something.
那天是我烧的警察局
It was me who burned down the police station.
除了你还会是谁?
Well, who the Hell else would it have been?
迪克森?
Dixon?
什么?
Yep?
你确定要这么干吗?
You sure about this?
你问我要不要杀了这个人吗?
About killing this guy?
不大确定
Not really.
你呢?
You?
不大确定
Not really.
我想我们可以路上决定
I guess we can decide along the way.